Prem Kumar G

Bengaluru • +91 9108274886 • prempro42@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/prem-kumar-g

Front-end Developer

Experienced professional with **5+ years** in **front-end development**, specializing in **React.js**. Passionate about crafting user-friendly, pixel-perfect interfaces while ensuring reusable and optimized code. Driven by a commitment to continuous learning and adapting to new tools and frameworks, I am always eager to embrace the latest technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Infosys • Bengaluru, KA

08/2022 - Present

Technology Lead

- A transformative project for Danske Bank, using in-house Micro Frontends in React. Collaborating closely with team & stakeholders to deliver user-centric solutions.
- Part of the Reduce Legacy Tribe, driving modernization efforts and enhancing system efficiency within the organization.
- Following Spotify Agile methodology to streamline development processes and ensure timely delivery of features. Thriving in a dynamic and collaborative environment.

Technology Analyst

- Implemented a subscription feature, expanding user capabilities and engagement.
- Enhanced application performance and maintainability using MobX for efficient state management.
- Resolved critical Jira bugs, ensuring a smooth workflow for users.

Blooms Mobility • Bengaluru, KA

01/2021 - 08/2022

Frontend Developer

- Established real-time, bidirectional communication between two Angular applications (including a PWA as a remote control) using WebSockets, ensuring seamless interaction and low-latency control.
- Led a team of 2 junior developers in implementing a state management using Redux, resulting in a 35% decrease in monthly expenses.
- Designed and implemented responsive user interfaces with Angular & React, leading to good app performance & improvement in user satisfaction.

VNR IT Solutions • Bengaluru, KA

02/2019 - 09/2020

Full Stack Developer

- Early Employee, Wore all Hats for the Company, from Designing, Coding, Training New Interns, Customer Support and Marketing.
- Worked Extensively on MyKidsDrawing (now beyondKlasses.) Project, got 10K+ Users onboard.
- Learnt developing RESTful Web APIs Using Spring Boot Framework (Java) with MySQL Database.
- Worked on Static Front-End Projects using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap & JavaScript.

SKILLS

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java
- React Libraries: React JS, Redux Toolkit, React Router, React Hook Form, Tanstack Query, Jest with React Testing Library

- UI Libraries: Material UI (MUI), Chakra UI, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Mantine, Bulma CSS
- Platforms: AWS, Vercel, Digital Ocean, Netlify, Render, Firebase, Cloudflare CDN
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB
- Tools / Others: VS Code, Postman, PWA, Git

PROJECTS

Anonymous Chat

React app that uses Socket.IO for real time chatting anonymously, built using Chakra UI, Vite & Node.js anonymous-chat-app-prem.vercel.app

Random Quotes

React app showcasing random inspirational quotes for daily motivation, built using Tailwind CSS & Vite random-quotes-daily.netlify.app

Portfolio

Simple static website with links to my certifications, profiles & small projects. $\underline{\text{prem-kumar-g.netlify.app}}$

CERTIFICATIONS

Responsive Web Design	12/2020
FreeCodeCamp	
React JS	11/2020
Udemy	
EDUCATION	

B.E in Mechanical Engineering

CMR Institute of Technology • Bengaluru, KA

06/2018